{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Queen Victoria","incorrectAnswers":["Queen Elizabeth II","Queen Mary","Queen Anne"],"question":"Which British queen did not go out in public for three years after the death of her husband in 1861?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Ronald Reagan","incorrectAnswers":["John Quincy Adams","Gerald Ford","James Polk"],"question":"Who was the 40th president of the USA, in term during the period 1981–1989?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Luke Skywalker","incorrectAnswers":["Han Solo","Lando Calrissian","Obi-Wan Kenobi"],"question":"In Star Wars, who is Princess Leia's twin brother?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Weezer","incorrectAnswers":["LMFAO","Static-X","The Black Keys"],"question":"Which alternative rock band from the United States released the studio album 'Hurley'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The causation of disease","incorrectAnswers":["Poisons","Schematic layouts","Men"],"question":"What is Aetiology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Tango","incorrectAnswers":["Treat","Turn","Tumble"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter T?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Back to the Future","incorrectAnswers":["Star Wars","Jurassic Park","The Goonies"],"question":"Which movie had a device known as a flux capacitor?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mao suit","incorrectAnswers":["Kurta","Sherwani","Nehru Jacket"],"question":"Which of these is a style of tunic suit worn in China?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"John Locke","incorrectAnswers":["Ludwig Wittgenstein","Socrates","Voltaire"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Good and evil, reward and punishment, are the only motives to a rational creature'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Cinq","incorrectAnswers":["Fünf","Cinco","Bleu"],"question":"What is the French word for 'five'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Croatia","San Marino","Bosnia and Herzegovina"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Austria?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"James II","incorrectAnswers":["Edward VII","Henry III","Charles I"],"question":"Who was the monarch of England during the time period 1685-1688?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Feta","incorrectAnswers":["Gouda","Mozzarella","Parmesan"],"question":"What type of cheese is used in a classic Greek salad?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Five","incorrectAnswers":["Six","Seven","Black"],"question":"In Italian, what is the meaning of the word 'cinque'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Jamaica","incorrectAnswers":["Chile","Brazil","Paraguay"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Kingston?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Henry VIII","incorrectAnswers":["George I","Henry VI","Richard III"],"question":"Who was the father of Elizabeth I?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Boxing","incorrectAnswers":["Rugby","Cricket","Football"],"question":"With which sport is Muhammad Ali associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1945","incorrectAnswers":["1938","1940","1943"],"question":"In what year of WW II did Russia declare war on Japan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Central America","incorrectAnswers":["Africa","Indonesia","Japan"],"question":"Where Is The Natural Habitat Of The Cheese Plant?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Congress","incorrectAnswers":["Supreme Court","Cabinet","House of Lords"],"question":"What part of the US government makes the laws?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Fortuna","incorrectAnswers":["Tyche","Jupiter","Vesta"],"question":"Who is the Roman goddess of destiny?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Khrushchev","incorrectAnswers":["Putin","Gorbachev","Lenin"],"question":"In 1953, Stalin Died. Who ultimately succeeded him as the leader of the Soviet Union?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bulgarian","incorrectAnswers":["Bulgarish","Bulgavite","Bulgarite"],"question":"What is the term for a person from Bulgaria?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Louis Armstrong","incorrectAnswers":["A-ha","Garbage","Jack White and Alicia Keys"],"question":"Who performed the theme song to the James Bond film On Her Majesty's Secret Service?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Frances Hodgson Burnett","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Louis Stevenson","Arthur Conan Doyle","Joseph Conrad"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Secret Garden'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Cream ","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Led Zeppelin","Prince"],"question":"Who released the album 'Strange brew '","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Football","Table tennis","Motor Racing"],"question":"With which sport is Serena Williams associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"George R. R. Martin","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Jack Vance","Edgar Rice Burroughs"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Dreamsongs: A RRetrospective'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Chainmail","incorrectAnswers":["Helmets","Shields","Leather jerkins"],"question":"Which of these is not a type of Viking armor?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bhutan","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Thailand","Cambodia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders People's Republic of China?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Water Babies","incorrectAnswers":["Oliver Twist","The Little Prince","The Prince and the Pauper"],"question":"Which famous book contains the line \"Once upon a time there was a little chimney sweep and his name was Tom\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Zanzibar and England","incorrectAnswers":["France and Mauritania","Belgium and The Netherlands","India and Fiji"],"question":"Between which countries was the shortest war in history, lasting 38 minutes?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Foreigner","incorrectAnswers":["Gotthard","The Velvet Underground","The Chicks"],"question":"Which Band Had A 1985 Number One Hit With The Single “I Wanna Know What Love Is”?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Holly Hunter","incorrectAnswers":["Angela Lansbury","Sidney Poitier","Emma Thompson"],"question":"Which actress played the role of Jane Craig in Broadcast News?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Flute","incorrectAnswers":["Ocarina","Castanets","Flugelhorn"],"question":"Which of these is a woodwind instrument?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jin Yong","incorrectAnswers":["C. S. Lewis","Edgar Rice Burroughs","J. K. Rowling"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Heaven Sword and Dragon Saber'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beach Boys","incorrectAnswers":["Swans","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American rock band released the song 'Blue Christmas'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ben Affleck","incorrectAnswers":["Keanu Reeves","Donald Sutherland","Christian Bale"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Batman in Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice and Justice League?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mardi","incorrectAnswers":["Merci","Maison","Mousse"],"question":"What is the French word for Tuesday?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"An Axe","incorrectAnswers":["A Hammer","A Gun","A Bow and Arrow"],"question":"What sort weapon was used by Jack Torrance in The Shining?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Apple","incorrectAnswers":["Microsoft","IBM","Amstrad"],"question":"Which company in 1984 advertised their new computer during the Super Bowl, and never re-used the commercial?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Eiffel Tower","incorrectAnswers":["The Statue of Liberty","Big Ben","The Colosseum"],"question":"Which iconic landmark was originally built for the 1889 World's Fair?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Javier Bardem","incorrectAnswers":["Jason Bateman","Ken Jeong","Sean Penn"],"question":"Which actor has featured in both No Country for Old Men and The Sea Inside?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Red, White, and Blue","incorrectAnswers":["Green, White, and Red","Yellow, White, and Blue","Red, White, and Yellow"],"question":"What colors are traditionally associated with the US Independence Day (4th of July)?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Zendaya","incorrectAnswers":["Emma Stone","Kirsten Dunst","Tobey Maguire"],"question":"Which actress has played MJ in Tom Holland's Spider-Man films?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Thailand","incorrectAnswers":["Indonesia","Mongolia","South Korea"],"question":"In which country is the city of Bangkok?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Let's Go Crazy\" by Prince","incorrectAnswers":["\"Jumpin', Jumpin'\" by Destiny's Child","\"I Write Sins Not Tragedies\" by Panic! at the Disco","\"Gimme More\" by Britney Spears"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Dearly beloved, we have gathered here today to get through this thing called life.\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Carpe vinum","incorrectAnswers":["Nil volentibus arduum","Memores acti prudentes future","Oderint dum metuant"],"question":"Which of these Latin phrases means 'Seize the wine'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Kokeshi","incorrectAnswers":["Kabuki","Karaoki","Origami"],"question":"What is the name given to traditional Japanese dolls with no arms or legs?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Isaac Asimov","incorrectAnswers":["Ursula K. Le Guin","Philip K. Dick","Stephen King"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Caves of Steel'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Gin ","incorrectAnswers":["Rum","Vodka","Avocaat"],"question":"The Term 'Dutch Courage' Originally Came From The Consumption Of Which Drink?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Golf","incorrectAnswers":["Cricket","Badminton","Surfing"],"question":"With which sport is Seve Ballesteros associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Spain","incorrectAnswers":["Seychelles","Eswatini","Estonia"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.es' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pierre-Auguste Renoir","incorrectAnswers":["Paul Cézanne","‎Pablo Picasso","Jan van Eyck"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Luncheon on the Boating Party\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"One Direction","incorrectAnswers":["The Beatles","Talking Heads","Backstreet Boys"],"question":"Which band did Zayn Malik belong to?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Viruses","incorrectAnswers":["Wine","Parasites","The therapeutic use of plants"],"question":"What is Virology the study of?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Cardinals","incorrectAnswers":["Bishops","Priests","Archdeacons"],"question":"Which group of people elect the pope?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Orange","incorrectAnswers":["Red","Blue","Purple"],"question":"What colour do you get when you mix yellow with red?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Shells","incorrectAnswers":["Large lined ones","Bibs","Little twine"],"question":"The pasta conchiglie has what meaning in Italian?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Jack","incorrectAnswers":["The Nightmare","The Flush","The Drone"],"question":"What Is The Name Of The White Ball In A Game Of Bowls?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Long Jump","incorrectAnswers":["High Jump","Triple Jump","Pole Vault"],"question":"Which Jump Event Did Carl Lewis Specialize In As Well As The Sprint?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Crane","incorrectAnswers":["Eagle","Condor","Stork"],"question":"What is the world's tallest flying bird species?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Maldives","incorrectAnswers":["Suriname","Ireland","Liechtenstein"],"question":"Male is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Audrey Hepburn","incorrectAnswers":["Tippi Hedren","Barbara Stanwyck","Sigourney Weaver"],"question":"Which actress played the role of Holly Golightly in Breakfast at Tiffany's?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"My Favorite Year","incorrectAnswers":["A Nightmare on Elm Street","The Searchers","Die Hard"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Alan Swann'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Lucitania","incorrectAnswers":["Olympic","Mary Rose","Mauretania"],"question":"What was name of the Titanic's sister ship?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Hunchback Of Natre Damme","incorrectAnswers":["A Tale of Two Cities","Les Miserables","The Count of Monte Cristo"],"question":"Which famous book begins with the line \"On January 6, 1482, the people of Paris were awakened by the tumultuous clanging of all the bells in the city\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Blondie","incorrectAnswers":["No Doubt","Siouxsie and the Banshees","Garbage"],"question":"Which band was founded and fronted by Debbie Harry and was nominated for the Grammy award for their song 'Call Me'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Rex","incorrectAnswers":["Max","Leo","Bob"],"question":"What is the second part of the title of the Sophocles play about the king of Thebes?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Tainted Love","incorrectAnswers":["99 Luftballoons","Whip It","No Rain"],"question":"What song did Soft Cell have a hit with in 1986?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Spinach","incorrectAnswers":["Kale","Broccoli","Cabbage"],"question":"Which vegetable did Popeye love to eat from a can?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Yellow","Gold","Maroon"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Singapore?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Fondant","incorrectAnswers":["Caramel","Ganache","Meringue"],"question":"What is the sugary paste used for icing and cake decor that comes from the French word for 'melting'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ralph Fiennes","incorrectAnswers":["Brian Cox","Mark Wahlberg","Leonardo DiCaprio"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including Schindler's List and Skyfall?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"England","incorrectAnswers":["Mexico","Philippines","Spain"],"question":"Fish & Chips is a dish that is most associated with which part of the world?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Open and Closed","incorrectAnswers":["Curved and Straight","Hairline and Fault line ","Partial and Complete"],"question":"What are the two main types of bone fracture?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Dardanelles","incorrectAnswers":["The Bering Strait","The English Channel","The Panama Canal"],"question":"During World War I, which strait between the Aegean and the Sea of Marmara was unsuccessfully contested by the Allies in 1915?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Buffalo Bills","incorrectAnswers":["Buffalo Raiders","Buffalo Bears","Buffalo City"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in Buffalo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Andy Warhol","incorrectAnswers":["Pablo Picasso","Salvador Dali","Edvard Munch"],"question":"Which Famous Artist Was Shot And Wounded By Valeria Solanis In 1968?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bahamas","incorrectAnswers":["Honduras","Colombia","Dominican Republic"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Nassau?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Afroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Austronesian","Uralic","Dravidian"],"question":"The language 'Egyptian Arabic' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"post-impressionism","incorrectAnswers":["Mannerism","Italian Renaissance","Dutch Golden Age"],"question":"The painting \"Portrait de L’artiste Sans Barbe\" by Vincent van Gogh is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Tiercel","incorrectAnswers":["A Dog","A Hob","A Billy"],"question":"What would you call a male hawk?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Grandmaster Flash and the Furious Five","incorrectAnswers":["Run-DMC","The Beastie Boys","Public Enemy"],"question":"What hip-hop group is the first to be inducted into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"HIM","incorrectAnswers":["Haloo Helsinki!","Amorphis","Hanoi Rocks"],"question":"Which Finnish rock band released the studio album 'Screamworks: Love in Theory and Practice'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Canada","incorrectAnswers":["United States of America","Russia","Indonesia"],"question":"Which Country Has The Most Coastline?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Class action","incorrectAnswers":["Criminal suit","Civil litigation","Small claims"],"question":"What is the name of the type of lawsuit that represents the common interests of a large group?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Mascarpone","incorrectAnswers":["Feta","Gouda","Mozzarella"],"question":"What type of cheese is used to make a Tiramisu?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1865","incorrectAnswers":["1851","1832","1801"],"question":"In What Year Did The American Civil War End?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Thunder","incorrectAnswers":["Sonar","Gong","Clang"],"question":"What is the sound that is caused by a bolt of lightning?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Maryland","incorrectAnswers":["Pennsylvania","Virginia","Baltimore"],"question":"In which state was `The Blair Witch Project' set","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"South Sudan","incorrectAnswers":["Russia","Seychelles","Switzerland"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.ss' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stephen King","incorrectAnswers":["H. P. Lovecraft","Edgar Allan Poe","Jack Vance"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Just After Sunset'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Dickens","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hardy","James Joyce","Emily Brontë"],"question":"Who wrote \"A Christmas Carol\"?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Gustave Courbet","incorrectAnswers":["Caravaggio","René Magritte","‎Pablo Picasso"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Sleepers\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Poland ","incorrectAnswers":["South Africa","Mongolia","Ireland"],"question":"In which country is the city of Plock?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Oscar Wilde","incorrectAnswers":["Edgar Allen Poe","Victor Hugo","William Shakespeare"],"question":"Whose works the \"Ballad Of Reading Gaol\" and \"De Profundis\" were written from his experiences in prison?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Afroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Indo-European","Kra–Dai","Uralic"],"question":"The language 'Mesopotamian Arabic' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Royal Family","incorrectAnswers":["The Kardashians","The Osmonds","The Gibbs"],"question":"In 1969 Richard Cawston Made A Documentary For The BBC About Which Famous Family?","difficulty":"hard"},